realdownloader.com 2015-04-19

# Privacy Policy | RealNetworks

**REALNETWORKS, INC., AND AFFILIATED ENTITIES**

_This document was last updated 31 January 2014._

This Privacy Policy covers RealNetworks, Inc., its majority-owned affiliates and worldwide subsidiaries, and RealNetworks divisions operating under different trade names, including GameHouse, Muzicall, and Zylom (collectively "RealNetworks" or "RN"). RealNetworks is committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. This Privacy Policy explains how RealNetworks collects and utilizes both personal and non-personal information when you use our products, mobile applications, services and websites “RN Online Services”.

RealNetworks processes information about our users on servers located in a number of countries. We may also subcontract processing or share your information to third parties located in countries other than your home country. Information collected by RealNetworks in the United States may, for example, be transferred to and processed in a country outside of the United States. Information collected within the European Economic Area and Switzerland may, for example, be transferred to, and processed in a country outside of the European Economic Area and Switzerland.

By submitting your personal information to us and our agents through the use of the RN Online Services you consent to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

By downloading or using any of the RN Online Services you are agreeing that you have read and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any part of this Privacy Policy then please do not use any of the RN Online Services.

## WHY DO WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?

RealNetworks collects personal information to improve the manner by which we operate and offer our RN Online Services, communicate with you, and provide effective customer support. We will not share your personally identifiable information with third parties without your consent, unless necessary for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

Personal information specifically identifies an individual and may include: name; email address; financial account information and other payment information submitted to us for order processing; mailing address; phone number; username and password; and device ID (including IP address)

## HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION? 

RealNetworks uses your personal information to:

  * Deliver to you and bill you for the RN Online Services, and communicate with you concerning your account and customer service issues, verify access rights to premium content or other access-restricted services and software;
  * Ask you to participate in surveys;
  * Offer you product upgrades, content, services and games;
  * Auto-update downloaded products;
  * Provide you with news, updates, targeted advertising, promotions, and special offers, including by combining your personal information with non-personal information, such as the amounts and types of purchases you make;
  * Allow interoperability with social media and other third party sites. When using this functionality, you should consult the privacy policy of such sites to determine the information practices of those sites; and
  * Further our business purposes, such as to perform data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, to enhance, improve or modify the RN Online Services, to identify usage trends, determine the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and to operate and expand our business activities.

We may send “transactional or relationship” communications to you, such as notices to facilitate a transaction you have conducted or messages that provide information about your existing account, using various electronic communication, including email and mobile communications. If, at any time, you decide you would rather not receive these types of communications from RealNetworks, you can opt-out by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any RealNetworks email or update the Contact Preferences for your RealNetworks account.

## WHAT NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

We collect non-personal information that does not permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, store, transfer, publish, promote, report and otherwise disclose non-personal information for any purpose, provided such information does not otherwise personally identify you. The following are examples of non-personal information that we collect: 

  * Information about your computer, hardware, software, platform, mobile device, Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * Language preference;
  * Gender;
  * Anonymous information regarding customer activities on our websites, which is aggregated and considered non-personal information for purposes of this Privacy Policy;
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies described in more detail later in this Privacy Policy.

## HOW DO WE USE YOUR NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION?

  * Improve our software and services by providing content recommendations, language and location customization, targeted advertising and/or personalized help and instructions;
  * Determine if you meet the minimum system requirements to use our products, and provide information concerning compatibility and interoperability;
  * Track content use for the purpose of paying royalties and license fees to third party providers;
  * Better understand how our products are used.

We also may share or disclose your personal information or the content of files you upload using the RN Online Services to comply with the law or respond to legal process or lawful requests, including from law enforcement and government agencies.

**THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING**

We allow third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our websites or interact with the RN Online Services. These companies use non-personal information about your visits in order to provide advertisements of interest to you. ****

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you use the RN Online Services. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. 

These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information and these technologies enable them to recognize a unique cookie that has been placed on your browser, which in turn enables us and these companies to learn which advertisements bring users to the RN Online Services.

In addition, we and these companies may use such technologies to track the actions of users of the RN Online Services, to measure statistics of our marketing efforts, and to deliver advertisements on the RN Online Services that may be more relevant to individual consumers and that will improve the consumer experience of the RN Online Services.

To learn more about behavioral advertising, or to opt-out of this type of advertising as conducted by our NAI partners (opt-out does not apply to advertising from non-NAI members), you can visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp%3Ehttp:/www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). RN is not an NAI member, and does not represent that it complies with all NAI standards.

Advertisements displayed on RealNetworks Web sites or embedded in other media content provided by RealNetworks may be delivered via an advertising management service. When you view a web page on our web site that contains advertising provided one of our advertising management services, the advertising service company may place a cookie on or retrieve a cookie from your computer if you have enabled cookies. This cookie may uniquely designate your computer/browser, without containing any personally identifying information such as your name or e-mail address. RealNetworks does not intentionally provide any of your personally 

When you search for specific content on RealNetworks web sites, the search terms may be embedded in the "search string" that appears in the URL display window of your web browser. Certain advertising services or third party content providers may associate these search strings with cookies they set or retrieve from our pages.

From time to time, RealNetworks enters into partnerships with other companies to provide you with the opportunity to:

  * sample or purchase a product or service; 
  * offer plug-ins, products and services that enhance the experience of using the RN Online Services, or;
  * offer the opportunity to participate in third-party or co-branded promotions, sweepstakes or special programs.

If you purchase a product or service developed or owned by another company, RealNetworks will seek your informed consent prior to giving that company information you provide to us. We will never sell, rent or disclose to third parties our customers' personally identifiable information collected from the distribution of RealNetworks products or gathered on a RealNetworks Web site unless we are required to do so by law or receive your advance informed consent.

RealNetworks offers a variety of "plug-in" products that are compatible with certain RealNetworks products. While we endeavor to fully research and disclose how such plug-ins utilize personal information, RealNetworks is not responsible for the operation of plug-ins provided by third parties and we strongly encourage you to visit their Web sites and read the privacy policies that govern their usage. RealNetworks will not provide personally identifiable information to our product plug-in partners without first obtaining the informed consent of our users.

For more information regarding our advertising and use of cookies on the RealNetworks websites, click [here](http://realnetworks.com/privacy-policy/specific-topics.aspx "here").

## HOW DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION SECURE?

RealNetworks is committed to protecting your personal information. We use the following controls to protect your personal information:

  * Use of secure connections using Secure Socket Layer Technology or SSL to safeguard information when transmitted from your Web browser to RealNetworks;
  * Use of security controls to restrict access to databases housing personally identifying information;
  * Use of encryption for sensitive personal information, such as credit card numbers and user names;
  * Limited employee access to databases containing personal information and confidentiality requirements imposed upon employees who do; and
  * Subcontractors bound by contractual, technical and organizational measures.

## PRIVACY ON SOCIAL NETWORKING SITES

When you use a RealNetworks product or game through a Social Networking Site such as Facebook (“SNS”), you allow RealNetworks to access certain personal and non-personal information that you provided to such SNS such as your user ID, first and last name, profile picture, and usage data for that product or game. By accessing a RealNetworks product or game through an SNS, you are authorizing RealNetworks to collect, store and use all information that you agreed the SNS could provide to RealNetworks through the SNS. RealNetworks’ collection, storage and use of your information is governed by this Privacy Policy.

When you link to the RN Online Services through any SNS please remember that you are bound by the privacy policy of the SNS and we do not control and are not responsible for the privacy practices of such sites.  You should consult the privacy policy of such sites to determine the information practices of those sites.

## WHEN AND HOW DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES?

RealNetworks does not use your personal information for purposes incompatible with those listed above. In some cases, access to certain products and services may require the provision of personal information to a third party. In such cases, this will be stated during the registration process, in the terms of use, through the distribution process, or in a similar manner. The third party's use of such information is governed by that party's privacy policy. Please visit the privacy policy of the third party to make sure you understand how they use the personal information you provide to them. If you do not wish for such a transfer to take place, you should not register for the applicable product or service. Additionally, RealNetworks may be required to provide specific access and usage information to certain content providers and rights holders as a condition of content licensing and royalties. 

RealNetworks may disclose relevant information about our customers to our contractors in order for them to provide specific services for RealNetworks such as website hosting, professional services, including information technology services and related infrastructure, customer service, e-mail delivery, auditing and other similar services. RealNetworks contractors are bound to keep all personal information they process confidential.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties in order to perform services you request or functions you initiate, such as when you post information and materials on message boards and forums, including on our Facebook Page.   When you post information in a public forum it becomes public information.  In addition, we may disclose your personal information in order to identify you to anyone to whom you send communications through the RN Online Services.

We may disclose your information to a third party in connection with a corporate reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock, including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings. 

RealNetworks may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law; (b) comply with the order of a competent judicial authority in any jurisdiction; (c) comply with legal process served on RealNetworks; (d) protect and defend the rights or property of RealNetworks; (e) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RealNetworks products or the public at large; or (f) to enforce our terms and conditions.

This Privacy Policy does not govern other sites that are linked to one of RN Online Services.

## E-MAIL FROM REALNETWORKS

Separate RealNetworks products, services and lines of business may send separate newsletters and marketing emails to you. You may opt out of receiving RealNetworks marketing messages. If you create an online account with RealNetworks, you can change your account setting to select whether you wish to receive marketing messages. However, we may continue to send you e-mails about RN Online Services you have previously purchased or to inform you about critical technical service issues relating to an RN Online Service.

## HOW TO ACCESS AND UPDATE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

To access your account information and preferences, select "Manage My Account" from the menus in the RealPlayer (usually under the "Help" menu) or other RealNetworks consumer software. Sign in to your account and modify your information and preferences as needed.

If you created an account with RealNetworks, you may review and update your account on the web at [www.real.com](http://www.real.com/ "www.real.com") or by selecting "My Account," and logging in using your name and password. If you have forgotten a username or password, you can use our [online help resources ](http://service.real.com/ "online help resources ")or contact customer service at: 1-866-420-5780 Monday - Friday, 8 am - 5 PM Pacific Time.

## USE OF COOKIES

We use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, and similar technologies to provide you with a tailored experience.

**What is a cookie?**  
A "cookie" is a small text file that is stored by your web browser on your computer or mobile device to store your preferences. This cookie policy relates to tracking technologies generally and therefore, for the purposes of this policy, references to “cookies” will incorporate references to all types of tracking technologies which require access to and storage of data or programs on your computer.

Cookies are not themselves personally identifiable, but may be linked to personal information that you provide to us through your interaction with the RN Online Services.  A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain (internet location) from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie (i.e. when does it expire), and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.

**How does RealNetworks use cookies?  
** Like many web and e-commerce sites, RealNetworks and our business partners use cookies to "recognize" your Internet browsing and RealNetworks software or apps in order to display information that is relevant to you and to cache some elements of the RealNetworks web sites and services to improve their performance. When you visit the RN Online Services, RealNetworks cookies are sent to our servers automatically.

Cookies allow us to customize your RealNetworks experience. When you return to RealNetworks web sites your settings are maintained and we can personalize content, banners, advertisements and promotions that you will see when you visit RN Online Services. 

RealNetworks does not require that you accept cookies, however, some functionality on our web sites, our product purchase check-out process, and our products and services may be impaired if you decline to accept cookies.

Any personally identifiable information that may be contained in our cookies is treated in accordance with our [Privacy Policy](http://realnetworks.com/privacy-policy/index.aspx).

**Types of Cookies Used by RealNetworks**

**Cookie Type**

| 

**Purpose**  
  
---|---  
  
**Functional**

| 

To recognize our users' preferences (playing webgames or downloading games, etc.) and remembering subscribers' and registered account holders' information such as username or ID.   
  
**Advertising**

| 

These are placed by RealNetworks or our partners for advertising purposes. Upon your return to our websites, we can personalize advertisements and promotions.   
  
**Analytics**

| 

To analyze how visitors use our websites. These cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come from and the pages they visited. These cookies help us understand traffic patterns on RN Online Services so that we can enhance your experience and provide you with more relevant information about our products and the content available on our web sites. 

[We only use Analytical/performance cookies that we think are helpful to you. These cookies allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily and do not encounter technical errors.]  
  
**Managing Cookies:  
** A number of privacy organizations publish guides on how to manage or disable web based cookies. Two of these are: [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) and [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

Most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings are typically found in the options or preferences menu in your browser. 

**Third Party Cookies:**  
The RN Online Services also use cookies and other technologies such as pixel tags, web beacons and clear GIF files, to help manage our online advertising program. These technologies are provided by our advertising partners and enable them to recognize a unique cookie that has been placed on your browser, which in turn enables us and these advertising partners to learn which advertisements bring users to the RN Online Services. 

In addition, we and our advertising partners may use these technologies to track the actions of users of the RN Online Services, to measure statistics of our marketing efforts, and to deliver advertisements on the RN Online Services that may be more relevant to individual consumers and that will improve the consumer experience on the RN Online Services. 

No personally identifiable information collected by RealNetworks is stored in these third party cookies. 

If you are concerned about third party cookies generated by advertisers you can visit one of the following sites to opt-out: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> (if you are in the U.S.) or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (if you are in Europe). **Use of Local Shared Objects or Flash Cookies:  
** Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies and cookie management tools available in a web browser may not remove flash cookies. To learn more about and to manage flash cookies visit: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>. 

Add-on extensions have also have been created for the Firefox web browser, for example Click&Clean: <https://addons.mozilla.org/en-us/firefox/addon/clickclean/reviews/>. 

**Retention of Cookies:  
** RealNetworks retains cookies to maximize the functionality of serving pages and content from our web sites, consistent with our [Privacy Policy](http://realnetworks.com/privacy-policy/index.aspx). Cookies that are set as part of subscription services will be active only for the duration of the subscription. 

Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after [two] years.

**For more information on our use of cookies, please see ourcookie policy**

## **CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY**

RealNetworks does not intentionally collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen (13). When a user discloses personal information on the RN Online Services, the user is representing to us that he or she is at least thirteen (13) years of age. If a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided us with personally identifiable information through the use of the RN Online Services, we ask that a parent or guardian e-mail us at privacy@realnetworks.com and we will delete the child’s information from our records.

## CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We frequently revise this Privacy Policy to keep it up to date with RealNetworks’ products, services and Web pages. Please check this page from time to time as your continued use of the RN Online Services after we publish our changes indicates acceptance to any changed terms.

## TRANSFER OF DATA TO OTHER COUNTRIES

RealNetworks processes information about our users on servers located in a number of countries. We may also subcontract processing or share your information to third parties located in countries other than your home country. Information collected by RealNetworks in the United States may, for example, be transferred to and processed in a country outside of the United States. Information collected within the European Economic Area and Switzerland may, for example, be transferred to, and processed in a country outside of the European Economic Area and Switzerland.

By submitting your personal information to us and our agents through the use of the RN Online Services you consent to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## SAFE HARBOR

RealNetworks complies with the U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks and has certified its personal information practices with the U.S. Department of Commerce under the Safe Harbor Program to ensure that your personal information is protected adequately in the event that your data is processed for the purposes of your agreement with us by a RealNetworks company in the United States. Should you want more information on the Safe Harbor principles, please go to: <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

If we require a RealNetworks company to process your data for the purposes of payment for goods and services this RealNetworks company will be RealNetworks, Inc., E Commerce LL; P.O. Box 91123, Seattle, Washington 98111-9223. The following data may be turned over to this company solely for the purpose of processing the payment transaction: your name, bank account, and amount to be charged. You have a right of access and rectification with regard to such data; to exercise these rights, or for other data privacy questions, please contact/send an email to:[privacy@realnetworks.com](mailto:privacy@realnetworks.com).

If you are a European resident and your data privacy complaint was not satisfactorily addressed by RealNetworks, you may contact the data protection authorities in the relevant jurisdiction.

A list of data protection authorities is available at: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>

RealNetworks has agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European Union data protection authorities to resolve disputes pursuant to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, as well as to cooperate and comply with the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland.

## NO ERROR FREE PERFORMANCE

RealNetworks does not guarantee error-free performance under this Privacy Policy. We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this Privacy Policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply. RealNetworks shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the United States.

## YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We ask for your consent (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us using the contact details set out below.

You have the right to access information held about you. [Any written request for access to information held about you may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing this information.] If you wish to do this, please contact us using the methods listed below.

## INTERNATIONAL

This English-language Privacy Policy is RealNetworks’ official statement of its Online Services privacy practices.  In case of any inconsistency between this English-language Privacy Policy and its translation into another language, this English-language document prevails.

## CHANGE OF CONTROL

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our products or services, the information concerning you that RealNetworks has retained, or would like to make a complaint, please contact: 

Privacy Policy Group  
RealNetworks, Inc.  
P.O. Box 91123  
Seattle, WA 98111-9233  
<https://realnetworks.zendesk.com/anonymous_requests/new>[ ](https://realnetworks.zendesk.com/anonymous_requests/new)

## CONTACT US ABOUT PRIVACY

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our products or services, the information concerning you that RealNetworks has retained, or would like to make a complaint, please contact: 

Privacy Policy Group  
RealNetworks, Inc.  
P.O. Box 91123  
Seattle, WA 98111-9233  

## PRIVACY RESOURCES ON THE WEB

Privacy is an important topic for Internet users. These organizations and government agencies provide information on privacy principles and how software applications interact with personal data.

  * Online Privacy Alliance — [http://www.privacyalliance.org/ ](http://www.privacyalliance.org/%C2%A0 "http://www.privacyalliance.org/ ")
  * TrustE — [http://www.truste.org/  ](http://www.truste.org/%C2%A0%C2%A0 "http://www.truste.org/  ")
  * BBB Online — <http://www.bbbonline.com/>[  ](http://www.bbbonline.com/ "http://www.bbbonline.com/  ")
  * PrivacyFoundation.org — <http://www.privacyfoundation.org/>[  ](http://www.privacyfoundation.org/ "http://www.privacyfoundation.org/  ")
  * Privacy Online: Fair Information Practices in the Electronic Marketplace (PDF file) — <http://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy2000/privacy2000.pdf>[  ](http://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy2000/privacy2000.pdf "http://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy2000/privacy2000.pdf  ")
  * Kids’ Privacy — <http://www.onguardonline.gov/articles/0031-kids-privacy>  
  * Center for Democracy & Technology: Data Privacy — <http://www.cdt.org/privacy/>[  ](http://www.cdt.org/privacy/ "http://www.cdt.org/privacy/  ")
  * Electronic Privacy Information Center: Privacy — <http://www.epic.org/privacy/>[  ](http://www.epic.org/privacy/ "http://www.epic.org/privacy/  ")
  * Department of Commerce: Internet Policy Task Force — <http://www.ntia.doc.gov/category/privacy>[ ](http://www.ntia.doc.gov/category/privacy "http://www.ntia.doc.gov/category/privacy ")
  * Federal Trade Commission: Privacy and Security — [http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html  ](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html "http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html  ")

## SPECIFIC TOPICS

For more information concerning specific functionality that may be relevant to privacy issues, visit our Specific Topics Index.
